Jonathan McIntosh

Littleton, Colorado (Willing to relocate for job) | 719-374-7471 | jonmcawesome2003@gmail.com

LinkedIn | Github | Blog | Website

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Passionate Full Stack Web Developer with a strong foundation in Python and JavaScript, complemented by a background in photography and customer service. Ever since I was a kid, knowledge has always been one of my biggest pursuits, and software is no exception. Attention to detail is one of my biggest strengths, with making sure that one element is styled *just right* or that photo is edited perfectly. I will also bring the virtues of patience and communication to the workplace. Driven by a deep interest in technology and a commitment to continuous learning, I bring technical expertise and creative insight to every project.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Javascript, React, Python, Flask, SQL, CSS, Tailwind, Digital Photography, Adobe Lightroom, Video Editing

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

TheLeMans100 - Github | Deployed Website

In celebration of 100 years of the endurance race held in LeMans, France this website was built.

- Used Javascript to append HTML to the DOM to make a dynamic website based on adding to removing from dataset
- Stylized the website using CSS with custom colors and fonts to make the visuals match the theme of the website
- · Collaborated with classmate to make all the assets and added functionality, like clicking the cars make an exhaust sound

TechHistoria - Github | Deployed Website

I have always found history and technology fascinating, so I decided to build a timeline that combines both

- Learned React and component to build a frontend, using props, state, and JSX
- Styled the HTML within the website using Tailwind, further solidifying my understanding of flexbox and styling
- Created a JSON backend with a Post feature with a controlled form to send new events to the backend

CarChronicle - Github | Demo

Using a web scraper, I was able to create a reasonably sized database to make an archive of car models and companies

- Used Python to establish classes and class methods, allowing to manipulate the SQLite tables
- Created a Seed file that uses a web scraper called beautiful soup to fill the database tables
- Used several Python components to create lists for the user to choose for better UX, and a loading bar for the seed file

InstaVibe - Github | Demo

Creating an Instagram Replica using Flask as a backend to build out my first full-stack project.

- First Full-Stack project, using React as our frontend and fetching from a Flask backend
- Creating a secure Login and Logout, Hashing the passwords in the backend with salt, secure key, not sending any sensitive data to the frontend
- Using Flask to create a RestFul API, Manipulating SQLite tables

LandmarkLore - Github | Demo

The term sonder comes to mind when I created this app, with the purpose being to tell stories anywhere in the world.

- Used Leaflet.js to create a navigable map, allowing users to tell stories and leave markers anywhere in the world
- Users may optionally upload photos to Cloudinary with their posts, deleted markers deleting it from the database
- Capstone project for Flatiron School

EXPERIENCE

Lake of the Trees Photographer + Videographer 100 Mile House, BC, Canada

08/2021 - Present

- Used a Nikon D7500 to capture thousands of photographs in manual mode of staff and campers
- Edited the RAW photos in Adobe Lightroom to enhance the quality of photo
- Used Final Cut Pro to compilate hundreds of photos and videos into a summary video of the week, and once a month for the staff
- Helped manage content for the YouTube and Website

H&R Block Client Service Representative Woodland Park, Colorado

01/2023 - 04/2023

ment Service Representative

Managed hundreds of appointments, received phone calls, and answered customers questions

Scanned hundreds of documents, and assisted the tax professional with various tasks

North Pole Santa's Workshop

Ride Operator

Cascade, Colorado 10/2022 - 12/2023

- Operated rides thousands of times safely and professionally, managing customer satisfaction.
- Answered any common questions they had, and helped keep the park clean and safe

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

Certified Full Stack Web Development, Python with Flask and JavaScript program

Denver, Colorado
02/2024 - 05/2024